(+91) 7795794208

govardhan.s92@gmail.com

## **Skills Synopsis**

Technical Skills: Angular, Typescript, Node JS, Express JS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery,

MEAN Stack, Java Web services, Mongodb, Redis, Elastic search, SQL, Webpack, Grunt, Karma,

Nginx, Jenkins, Docker, CI/CD, VSO, Git, SVN, Photoshop and more

Industries: IT Consulting, Healthcare

# **Experience Summary**

I'm a creative professional Full Stack Web Developer with over 4.8 years of experience in latest web design and development technologies in Oracle and Azure Cloud.

I have good exposure in developing single page applications, portals, hybrid apps, CRM platform apps together with strong understanding of best practices, analytical capabilities, organizational skills and ability to complete a successful implementation.

## **Professional Experience**

### Mobinius Technologies, Bangalore Senior Web Engineer

Jan 2019 - Present

Mobinius Technologies Pvt. Ltd. is an emerging technology company specializing in product development and solutions for Mobile, Windows and Mac OS platforms, applying disruptive technologies for business transformations. It brings great advantage to business space by bridging gaps, simplifying businesses and elevating competitive benefits by providing technology based business solutions.

- I was an integral part in all stages of product development lifecycle for Dutchview IT client.
- Worked on critical features of web app Real-time data sync, Chat app, Analytics, Performance etc. Collaborated with Product Managers, developers and designers of different teams to create rollout plans for different module.
- Develop Node JS based REST services for complex calculations, real-time data sync and chat application.
- Develop Angular solution with authentication, authorisation, routing, templates, directives, services, filters and custom solutions to meet requirements and optimise the performance.
- Validating user actions on the client side and providing responsive feedback.
- Unit testing with Karma.
- Automate, Optimise the development process with webpack, jenkins along with CI and CD.

## Cognizant, Bangalore Full Stack Web Developer

Apr 2016 - Dec 2018

Cognizant (NASDAQ-100: CTSH) is a world-leading professional services company, transforming business, operating and IT models for the digital era. Cognizant is an American multinational corporation that provides IT services, including digital, technology, consulting, and operations services. It is headquartered in Teaneck, New Jersey, United States.

- I worked on various products for companies like MICROSOFT and ORACLE marketplace.
- Worked on critical features of web app Single Sign-on (SSO), Analytics, Performance etc. Collaborated with Product Managers, developers and designers of different teams to create rollout plans for different module.
- Develop Angular solution with authentication, authorisation, routing, templates, directives, services, filters and custom solutions to meet requirements and optimise the performance.
- Validating user actions on the client side and providing responsive feedback.
- Unit testing with Karma.
- Develop Node JS based REST services for complex calculations.
- Develop Java based REST services comprising PL/SQL as database.
- Automate, Optimise the development process with webpack, grunt along with CI and CD.
- Enhance the application to native android app using WebView concept of Cordova.

## Indegene, Bangalore Web Developer

May 2015 - Apr 2016

Indegene offers research and development and management solutions to healthcare and pharmaceutical enterprises. It was founded in 1998 and is based in Bangalore, India and maintains offices internationally.

- Worked on various global brands of companies like PFIZER, GE Healthcare etc.
- Worked with designers for standardising Email and Web Experience of web app.
- Develop Veeva CRM web app targeting iOS devices like Mac and iPads.
- Develop Native app compatible using XCode with WebView concept for iOS devices.
- Develop Email templates for enhance sales marketing.
- Capture analytics like user clicks, time spent, user interests and many more.
- Cross Browser compatibility testing.

#### **Awards**

Title	Institution
Best Performer of the month	Indegene
Aspire Double Up Award	Indegene
Wah Points, Brownie Points	Cognizant

#### **Publications**

Title	URL
Portfolio	https://govardhan-srinivas.github.io
LinkedIn	https://www.linkedin.com/in/govardhan-srinivas
Blog	https://medium.com/@govardhan.s

### https://www.npmjs.com/package/excel-npv

#### **Excel NPV**

## **Certifications**

NIIT, Bangalore Code School Cognizant Cognizant

#### Course

Post Graduation in Java Real time web with Node Frontend Web Developer Full Stack Web Developer

# **Education**

### Institution

Visvesvaraya Technological University, India Sarvodaya Pre-university College, Tumkur, India B. G National Public School, Bangalore, India

#### Degree

Bachelor of Engineering - 69% XII - 78% X - 88%